Inventory of the Germany (Territory Under Allied Occupation, 1945-1955) records
Hoover Institution Archives
An Inventory of the Germany (Territory Under Allied Occupation, 1945-1955) records
80196
Germany (Territory Under Allied Occupation, 1945-1955)
55 manuscript boxes (22 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The records relate to demilitarization, denazification, democratization, and reconstruction of Germany after World War II. Includes minutes, reports, memoranda, laws, proclamations, press releases, agenda, and bulletins.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Germany (Territory under Allied Occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone) Office of Military Government for Bavaria. Kreis Traunstein Records Hoover Institution Archives
Germany (Territory under Allied Occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone) Office of Military Government Records, 1943-1950, Hoover Institution Archives
Historical Note
The Allied powers that defeated Nazi Germany in World War II divided the country into three zones of occupation: American, British, and Soviet. Each zone was ruled by the Commander-in-Chief of the respective occupational forces. The French zone was added in December 1946. Matters that affected Germany as a whole, however, would have to be decided jointly by all three Commanders-in-Chief, who for this purpose formed a single organ of control called the Control Council.
The purpose of the Allied Control Council was to deal with the central administration of the country. The Potsdam Agreement of 2 August 1945 further specified the tasks of the Control Council. Key items in the occupiers' agenda were the five D's: Denazification, Democratization, Dismantling, Disarming and Decentralization.
As relations between the Western Allies (especially the United States and the United Kingdom) and the Soviet Union quickly deteriorated, and so did their cooperation in the administration of occupied Germany. As early as in September 1946, disagreement arose regarding the distribution of coal for industry in the four occupation zones, and the Soviet representative in the council withdrew his support of the plan agreed upon by the governments of the United States, Britain and France.
Against Soviet protests, the two English-speaking powers pushed for an economic collaboration between the different zones, and on 1 January 1947 the British and American zones merged to form the Bizone and later the Trizone (after inclusion of the French zone).
Over the course of 1947 and early 1948 they began to prepare the currency reform that would introduce the Deutsche Mark, and ultimately the creation of an independent West German state. When the Soviets learned about this, they claimed that such plans were in violation of the Potsdam Agreement, that the Western powers were not interested in further regular four-power control of Germany, and that under such circumstances the Control Council had no purpose anymore.
On 20 March 1948, Marshal Vasiliy Sokolsky, the Soviet representative, walked out of the meeting of the Council, never to return. As the Control Council could only act with the agreement of all four members, this move basically shut down the institution, while the Cold War reached an early high point during the Soviet blockade of Berlin.
The Western powers instituted the Allied High Commission by September 1949 which remained in operation until 1955. In Eastern Germany, the Soviet administration with its representative of the ACC was the highest authority, later this position was converted to a High Commissioner as well, until the German Democratic Republic gained sovereignty.
Germany remained under nominal military occupation until 15 March 1991, when the final ratification of the Treaty on the Final Settlement With Respect to Germany (signed on 12 September 1990) was lodged with the German Government.
Scope and Content of Collection
The records relate to demilitarization, denazification, democratization, and reconstruction of Germany after World War II. Includes minutes, reports, memoranda, laws, proclamations, press releases, agenda, and bulletins.
The collection represents materials documenting the efforts of economic rehabilitation of Germany under Allied Control Authority Coordinating Committee (ACAC) and covers the varied national and international civilian and military apparatus that evolved.
The documents illustrate the diverse approaches of the Americans, British, and Russians in efforts to combat hunger, disease, and crime, preserve cultural artifacts, re-establish industry and utilities, and resolve important problems involving currency, housing, education, newspapers, elections, and displaced persons.
Arrangement
Records are arranged as originally received from the organization; generally by Office of Military Government (U.S. Zone)
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Military government.; Germany.; Germany--History--1945-1955.
Collection Contents
- Allied Control Authority Coordinating Committee (ACAC), 1945-1949 (Box 1-55)
  - General, 1945-1948 (Folder 1-4)
    - Directives, memoranda, and reports, 1947 (Folder 1:1-9)
    - Directives, memoranda, and reports, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 2:1-10)
    - Directives, memoranda, and reports, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 3:1-3)
    - Directives, memoranda, and reports, 1948 (Folder 3:4-8)
    - Summary of Financial Situation in Germany and Objectives of the Allied Control Authority (in Financial Policy), 1945 (Folder 3:9)
    - Reports to the Council of Foreign Ministers, 1947 (Folder 3-4)
      - Section I-Demilitarization (Folder 3:10)
      - Section II-Denazification (Folder 3:11)
      - Section III-Democratization (Folder 3:12)
      - Section IV-Level of Industry and Industrial Production (Folder 4:1-3)
      - Section V-Reparation (Folder 4:4)
      - Section VI-Central Administration (Folder 4:5)
    - Report on the Decisions of the Allied Control Authority in the Field of Agriculture, Forestry and Fishing, 1946 (Folder 4:6)
  - Control Council (CONL), 1945-1947 (Folder 4-5)
    - Reports, 1947 (Folder 4:7-13)
    - Reports, 1947 (Folder 5:1-2)
    - Minutes, 1945-1947 (Folder 5:4-9)
    - Agenda, 1946-1947 (Folder 5:10)
    - Index to papers and minutes, Allied Secretariat, 1946-1947 (Folder 5:11)
    - Index to papers and minutes, Coordinating, 1946 (Folder 5:12)
  - Directorate of Reparations, Deliveries and Restitution (DRDR), 1946-1948 (Folder 6-8)
    - Agenda, 1946-1947 (Folder 6:1)
    - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 6:2-6)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1947 (Folder 6:7-9)
    - Permanent Secretariat, 1946-1948 (Folder 6:10-13)
    - Permanent Secretariat, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 7:1-11)
    - Permanent Secretariat, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 8:1-10)
    - Restitution Procedures Committee (RPC), 1946-1947 (Folder 8)
      - Agenda, 1946-1947 (Folder 8:11)
      - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 8:12)
      - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 8:13)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 8:14)
    - Inter-Allied Reparation Agency (IARA), memoranda, 1947 (Folder 8:15)
  - Directorate of Economics (DECO), 1946-1948 (Folder 9-10)
    - Permanent Reparation Secretariat (PRSEC), 1946-1947 (Folder 9:1-2)
    - Committee for Liquidation of German War Potential (CLWP), 1946-1948 (Folder 9)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 9:3-8)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 9:9)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 9:10)
    - I.G. Farben Control Committee (COIG), 1946-1947 (Folder 9)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 9:11)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 9:12)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 9:13)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 9:14)
    - Price Control Committee (CPC), 1946-1947 (Folder 9-10)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 9:15)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1947 (Folder 10:1-4)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 10:5)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 9:6)
    - Trade and Commerce Committee (CT&C), 1946-1948 (Folder 10)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 10:7)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 10:8)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 10:9)
      - Inter-Zonal Trade Sub-Committee (SCIT), 1947-1948 (Folder 10)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 10:10)
        - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 10:11)
      - Rationing Sub-Committee (SCR), 1946-1948 (Folder 10)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 10:12)
        - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 10:13)
        - Minutes, 1946-1948 (Folder 10:14)
        - Notes by Secretariat, 1947-1948 (Folder 10:15)
      - Export and Import Sub-Committee (SE&I), 1947-1948 (Folder 10)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 10:16)
        - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 10:17)
      - Special Working Party on Consumers' Co-Operatives (SWPC), 1947-1948 (Folder 10)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 10:18)
        - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 10:19)
    - Fuel Committee (FC) and Oil Sub-Committee (CFUL), Minutes, 1948 February 28 (Folder 10:20)
    - Food and Agriculture Committee (FACO), 1946-1948 (Folder 10-11)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 9:15)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 11:1-3)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 11:4)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:5)
      - Duty Secretary (SEC), 1947 (Folder 11:6)
      - Education and Research Sub-Committee (E&RSC), minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:7)
      - Forestry Sub-Committee (FSC), agenda and minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:8)
      - Veterinary Sub-Committee (VSC), agenda and minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:9)
    - Industry Committee (CIND), 1947-1948 (Folder 11-12)
      - Chemical Industry Sub-Committee (SCCM), 1947-1948 (Folder 11)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 11:10-12)
        - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 11:13)
        - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:14)
      - Textiles and Consumer Goods Sub-Committee (SCCG), 1947-1948 (Folder 11)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 11:15)
        - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 11:16)
        - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:17)
      - Metals Sub-Committee (SKCMT), 1947 (Folder 11)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 11:18)
        - Agenda and minutes, 1947 (Folder 11:19)
      - Machinery and Optics Sub-Committee (SCMO), 1947-1948 (Folder 12)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 12:1)
        - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 12:2)
        - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 12:3)
        - Duty Secretary, 1947 (Folder 12:4)
  - Directorate of Finance (DFIN), 1946-1948 (Folder 12-15)
    - Agenda, 1946-1948 (Folder 12:5)
    - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 12:6-10)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1948 (Folder 12:11-12)
    - Memoranda, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 13:1-2)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 13:3-10)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 14:1-11)
    - Miscellany, 1946-1948 (Folder 15:1-2)
    - Committees, memoranda, agenda, and minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 15)
      - Price Policy (PPC), 1946-1947 (Folder 15:3)
      - Insurance (INS), 1947 (Folder 15:4)
      - Property Control (PC), 1947 (Folder 15:5-6)
      - Financing of Occupation Costs (FOC), 1947 (Folder 15:7)
      - Balancing of Foreign Accounts (CBFA), 1947 (Folder 15:8)
      - Financing Reparations Costs (FRC), 1947 (Folder 15:9)
      - Banking (BC), 1947 (Folder 15:10-11)
      - Public Finance (PF), 1947 (Folder 15:12)
      - Taxation (TC), 1947 (Folder 15:13-14)
  - Directorate of Economics (DFIN), 1946-1948 (Folder 12-15)
    - Agenda, 1946-1948 (Folder 12:5)
    - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 12:6-10)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1948 (Folder 12:11-12)
    - Memoranda, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 13:1-2)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 13:3-10)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 14:1-11)
    - Miscellany, 1946-1948 (Folder 15:1-2)
    - Committees, memoranda, agenda, and minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 15)
      - Price Policy (PPC), 1946-1947 (Folder 15:3)
      - Insurance (INS), 1947 (Folder 15:4)
      - Property Control (PC), 1947 (Folder 15:5-6)
      - Financing of Occupation Costs (FOC), 1947 (Folder 15:7)
      - Balancing of Foreign Accounts (CBFA), 1947 (Folder 15:8)
      - Financing Reparations Costs (FRC), 1947 (Folder 15:9)
      - Banking (BC), 1947 (Folder 15:10-11)
      - Public Finance (PF), 1947 (Folder 15:12)
      - Taxation (TC), 1947 (Folder 15:13-14)
  - Directorate of Internal Affairs and Communications (DIAC), 1946-1948 (Folder 16-25)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1948 (Folder 16:1-11)
    - Memoranda, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 17:1-3)
    - Agenda, 1946-1948 (Folder 17:4-5)
    - Minutes, 1946-1948 (Folder 17:6-13)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 18:1-12)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1947 (Folder 19:1-8)
    - Allied Communications and Posts Committee (ACPC), 1946-1948 (Folder 19-24)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 19:9-12)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 19:13-14)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 20:1-14)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 21:1-4)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 21:5-7)
      - Communications Sub-Committee (CSC), 1947-1948 (Folder 21-22)
        - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 21:8)
        - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 21:9-11)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 21:12-13)
        - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 22:1-4)
        - Radio Working Party (RWP), 1947-1948 (Folder 22:5-9)
        - Lines Working Party (LWP), 1947 (Folder 22:10-11)
      - Postal Sub-Committee (PSC), 1947-1948 (Folder 22-23)
        - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 22:12)
        - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 22:13)
        - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 22:14-15)
        - Minutes, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 23:1-2)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 23:3-9)
        - Stamps Working Party (SWP), 1947 (Folder 23:10)
      - Organization and Finance Sub-Committee (OFSC), 1947-1948 (Folder 23-24)
        - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 23:11)
        - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 23:12-13)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 24:1-3)
        - Allied Working Party for International Accounting (FWP), 1947 (Folder 24:4-7)
    - Allied Education Committee (AEC), 1947-1948 (Folder 24)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 24:8)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 24:9-10)
      - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 24:11-12)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 24:13)
    - Allied Public Safety Committee (APSC), 1947 (Folder 24)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 24:14)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 24:15)
      - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 24:16)
    - Allied Religious Affairs Committee (ARFC), 1947-1948 (Folder 25)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 25:1)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 25:2)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:3)
      - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 25:4)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 25:5)
    - Civil Administration Committee (CAC), 1946-1947 (Folder 25)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 25:6)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 25:7)
      - Memoranda, 1946-1947 (Folder 25:8)
      - Civil Service Working Party (CSWP), 1947 (Folder 25:9)
      - Census Registration Working Party (CRWP), 1947 (Folder 25:10)
    - Allied Health Committee (HEALTH), 1947-1948 (Folder 25)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:11)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:12)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:13)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:14)
      - Narcotics Control Working Party (NCWP), 1947 (Folder 25:15-18)
    - Allied Welfare Committee (WELFARE), 1947-1948 (Folder 25)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 25:19)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 25:20)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 25:21)
    - Intelligence Committee (INTC), 1947 (Folder 25)
      - Censorship Sub-Committee (SCC), 1947 (Folder 25:22)
      - Counter Intelligence Working Party (CIWP), 1947 (Folder 25:12)
  - Manpower Directorate (DMAN), 1946-1948 (Folder 26-27)
    - Agenda (P), 1946-1948 (Folder 26:1-2)
    - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 26:3-6)
    - Memoranda, 1947 (Folder 26:7-9)
    - Duty Secretary, 1946-1948 (Folder 26:10)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 26:11-15)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 27:1-3)
  - Legal Directorate (DLEG), 1946-1948 (Folder 27-29)
    - Duty Secretary, 1946-1948 (Folder 27:1-3)
    - Agenda, 1946-1947 (Folder 27:4-9)
    - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 27:10-11)
    - Minutes, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 28:1-10)
    - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 28:11-13)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 29:1-6)
  - Military Directorate (DMIL), 1946 (Folder 29)
    - Agenda, 1946 (Folder 29:7)
    - Minutes, 1946 (Folder 29:8)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946 (Folder 29:9)
    - Miscellany, 1946 (Folder 29:10)
  - Naval Directorate (DNAV), 1946 (Folder 29)
    - Agenda P, 1946 (Folder 29:11)
    - Minutes, 1946 (Folder 29:12)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946 (Folder 29:13)
    - German Hydrographic Institute (GHI), 1946 (Folder 29)
      - Minutes, 1946 (Folder 29:14)
      - Memoranda, 1946 (Folder 29:15)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946 (Folder 29:16)
    - Steering Committee (SC), 1946 (Folder 29:17)
  - Combined Service Directorate (DOCS), 1947-1948 (Folder 29-31)
    - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 29:18)
    - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 29:19)
    - Minutes, (contd.), 1947-1948 (Folder 30:1-4)
    - Memoranda, 1948 (Folder 30:5)
    - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 30:6-9)
    - Duty Secretary, 1947 (Folder 30:10-14)
    - Duty Secretary, (contd.), 1947 (Folder 31:1-3)
    - Air Committee (AIR), 1947 (Folder 31)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 31:4)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 31:5)
    - Committee on Meteorology (MET), 1947 (Folder 31)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 31:6)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 31:7)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 31:8)
    - Military Committee (MIL), 1947 (Folder 31)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 31:9)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 31:10)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 31:11)
    - Naval Committee (NAV), 1947 (Folder 31)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 31:12)
      - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 31:13)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 31:14)
      - German Hydrographic Institute (GHI), Board of Directors, 1947 (Folder 31:15-17)
      - Duty Secretary, 1947 (Folder 31:18)
  - Political Directorate (DPOL), 1946-1948 (Folder 31-33)
    - Minutes, 1946-1948 (Folder 31:19-23)
    - Minutes, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 32:1-4)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1948 (Folder 32:5-9)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 32:10-15)
    - Information Committee (INFC), 1947-1948 (Folder 32-33)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 32:16)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 32:17-18)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 33:1)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 33:2)
  - Directorate of Prisoners of War and Displaced Persons (DPOW), 1946-1948 (Folder 33-34)
    - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 33:3)
    - Minutes, 1947 (Folder 33:4-7)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 33:8-13)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1948 (Folder 34:1-3)
    - Miscellany, 1947 (Folder 34:4-6)
  - Directorate of Transport (DTPT), 1946-1948 (Folder 34-37)
    - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 34:7)
    - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 34:8-9)
    - Memoranda, 1948 (Folder 34:10)
    - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 35:11-15)
    - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947-1948 (Folder 35:1-7)
    - Miscellany, 1946-1947 (Folder 36:8-15)
    - Inland Waterways Committee (IWTC), 1946-1948 (Folder 36)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:1)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:2)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:3)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1948 (Folder 36:4)
      - Miscellany, 1947 (Folder 36:5-6)
    - Highways and Highway Transport Committee (HYTP), 1947-1948 (Folder 36)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:7)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:8-9)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 36:10)
      - Miscellany, 1947 (Folder 36:11)
    - Movements Working Party (MWP), 1947-1948 (Folder 36:12)
    - Ports and Coastal Shipping Committee (PCSC), 1946-1948 (Folder 36)
      - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:13)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:14)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:15)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 36:16)
    - Railway Committee (RAIL), 1947-1948 (Folder 36)
      - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 36:17)
      - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 36:18)
      - Memoranda, 1948 (Folder 36:19)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 36:20-21)
      - Budget, 1947 (Folder 36:22)
      - Secretariat papers, 1947-1948 (Folder 37:1-2)
      - Mechanical Sub-Committee (MECH), 1947-1948 (Folder 37)
        - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 37:3)
        - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 37:4)
      - Tariff Sub-Committee (TC), 1947-1948 (Folder 37)
        - Agenda, 1947-1948 (Folder 37:5)
        - Minutes, 1947-1948 (Folder 37:6)
        - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Folder 37:7)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 37:8)
        - Secretariat papers, 1947 (Folder 37:9)
  - German External Property Commission (GEPC), 1946-1947 (Folder 37)
    - Agenda, 1947 (Folder 37:10)
    - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Folder 37:11)
    - Memoranda, 1946-1947 (Folder 37:12)
    - Secretariat papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 37:13)
    - Information Pooling Committee (IPC), 1946 (Folder 37:14)
    - Inter-Allied Reparation Agency (IARA), 1946-1947 (Folder 37:15)
      See also box 8
  - Official Gazette of the Control Council for Germany, Berlin, Allied Secretariat, 1946-1948 (Folder 37:16-18)
  - Summary of Principal Differences in Quadripartite Report for the Council of Foreign Ministers, circa 1945 (Folder 38:1)
  - Monthly Report No.7, Fuel Committee, 1947 (Folder 38:2)
  - Allied Kommandatura Berlin (BK), 1947-1948 (Folder 38-40)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1947-1948 (Folder 38-40)
      - Deputy Commandants (BKD), 1947-1948 (Folder 38:3-12)
      - Deputy Commandants (BKD), (contd.), 1947-1948 (Folder 39:1-3)
      - Commandants', 1947-1948 (Folder 39:4-9)
      - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, United States, France, Great Britain (USSR/US/FR/BR), 1947-1948 (Folder 39:10)
      - USSR/US/FR/BR, (contd.), 1947-1948 (Folder 40:1-10)
    - Orders, 1946-1948 (Folder 40:11)
  - Bipartite organization (Bizone), 1946-1949 (Folder 41-54)
    - Directory, 1947-1948 (Folder 41:1)
    - Situation as at 1st 1947, map and production chart by Economic Control Group, 1947 October (Folder 41:2)
    - Board (BIB), 1946-1949 (Folder 41-44)
      - Agenda, 1947-1949 (Folder 41:3)
      - Minutes, 1947-1949 (Folder 41:4-10)
      - Secretariat papers, 1946-1949 (Folder 41:11-13)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1949 (Folder 42:1-9)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1949 (Folder 43:1-10)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1946-1949 (Folder 44:1-9)
    - Control Office (BICO), 1946-1949 (Folder 44-50)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947-1949 (Folder 44:10)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947-1949 (Folder 45:1-10)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947-1949 (Folder 46:1-13)
      - Secretariat papers, (contd.), 1947-1949 (Folder 47:1-12)